Concrete holds the daytime heat
Underneath our quiet feet
The sun is leaning low and wide
Against the rusty railing side
The dust of afternoon is gone
A cool gust sweeps the rooftop lawn
You pull your jacket zipper high
And look out at the changing sky
No need to rush, no need to say
How fast the light is slipped away
I watch the wind lift up your collar
The city sounds are getting smaller
Feel the breeze along
the concrete edge
Where the warm day
meets the cold blue air
We don't have to make a promise now
Or explain the reasons we are there
Just let the horizon turn to gray
As the afternoon fades away
The brick wall holds a steady glow
While everything is moving slow
A paper plane is floating down
Above the streets of this busy town
You trace a line along the metal rail
The shadows growing long and pale
I see the orange turn to blue
The wind is blowing close to you
Your shoulder shifts a little near
The quiet path is getting clear
Feel the breeze along
the concrete edge
Where the warm day
meets the cold blue air
We don't have to make a promise now
Or explain the reasons we are there
Just let the horizon turn to gray
As the afternoon fades away
The air gets thin,
the wind gets light
Between the sunset and the night
I look at you and catch your gaze
Underneath the dusty haze
We stay right here and watch the sky
Letting all the rush go by
Feel the breeze along
the concrete edge
Where the warm day
meets the cold blue air
Just let the horizon turn to gray
As the afternoon fades away
Concrete holds the evening cool
Underneath our quiet rule
Where the wind first swept the edge
Along the rooftop ledge
Rose and peach, gold and blue
Watching the sky fold into you
The clouds are drifting
in a quiet line
Like thoughts we don't have to define
The sun is dipping
down behind the towers
We've spent the whole
afternoon counting hours
No clock is ticking
on this dusty roof
We don't need any other kind of proof
Oh, see the peach turn into violet
A soft wave washing over the sky
The day is slipping down so quiet
As the warm colors multiply
I don't need to ask
where we are going
I just like the way
the sky is glowing
Your fingers trace
the warm brick wall
The shadows on the roof grow tall
The city traffic is a distant stream
A quiet current in a golden dream
You look at me and
let out a soft sigh
As a quiet airplane crosses by
Oh, see the peach turn into violet
A soft wave washing over the sky
The day is slipping down so quiet
As the warm colors multiply
I don't need to ask
where we are going
I just like the way
the sky is glowing
Rose turns to lavender,
gold turns to gray
Everything is shifting
at the end of the day
But standing right
here in the quiet space
I see the sunset color on your face
Oh, see the peach turn into violet
A soft wave washing over the sky
I don't need to ask
where we are going
I just like the way
the sky is glowing
Peach and violet, fading fast
A quiet moment earned at last
Watching the sky turn blue
Right next to you
Left side plays the bassline low
Right side makes the melody grow
Connected by a single thread
With nothing left
that needs to be said
You pull the white cord
from your pocket coat
And find a track that we both know
One side for you, one side for me
Sitting on the step
as quiet as can be
The wire stretches
loose between us two
A bridge of silver under sky of blue
We feel the kick-drum start to play
Chasing the noise of the day away
Your head is nodding
to the steady beat
A simple rhythm making us complete
Shared wired earbuds,
sharing the sound
Of a song that keeps
our feet on the ground
You hear the harmony,
I hear the rhyme
We're moving together,
one note at a time
No words are needed
when the music is close
This is the feeling
that I love the most
The acoustic guitar
starts to warm the track
We lean our shoulders slightly back
A siren hums four streets away
But in our ears, the
quiet vocals stay
You adjust the wire
with a gentle touch
A small gesture that means so much
Shared wired earbuds,
sharing the sound
Of a song that keeps
our feet on the ground
You hear the harmony,
I hear the rhyme
We're moving together,
one note at a time
No words are needed
when the music is close
This is the feeling
that I love the most
The bridge of the song
has a beautiful space
A quiet piano that fits this place
We listen in silence,
holding the line
Wishing this track could outrun time
Shared wired earbuds,
sharing the sound
Connected together, safe and sound
No words are needed
when the music is close
This is the feeling
that I love the most
Left side plays the fading chord
Right side is a quiet reward
Connected by a silver thread
Just like you said
Condensation on the aluminum side
A little chill we don't have to hide
You place the soda on the rusty rail
Where the old green
paint is getting pale
A drop of water runs along the side
Catching the light
that is trying to hide
You push the can towards my hand
On this high ledge above the land
It's cold against the
warm air of the roof
A quiet touch that needs no proof
We share the drink
in the fading light
While the city prepares for the night
Cold soda can on the warm metal rail
A silver spark that will not fade
We don't need a map or a secret sign
Just sitting right
here on the border line
The water drops are sliding down
High above the busy town
The fizzing sound is light and low
Like the breeze that
has started to blow
You take a sip and look away
With nothing more that we need to say
The contrast of the cold and the heat
Is like the quiet rhythm of our feet
Cold soda can on the warm metal rail
A silver spark that will not fade
We don't need a map or a secret sign
Just sitting right
here on the border line
The water drops are sliding down
High above the busy town
The sunset reflects on the silver top
We watch the tiny droplets stop
A simple cold drink we share today
Carrying the heat of the day away
Cold soda can on the warm metal rail
A simple comfort that will prevail
High above the busy town
As the sun goes down
Just a drop of water
on the metal track
A cold soda can, and
we're not looking back
Warm metal, cold breeze
Sitting at ease
Gold dust shimmers in the air
Reflections dancing everywhere
(Electric vibraphone
enters with warm tremolo)
The glass towers across the street
Are catching fire in the sunset heat
Every window is a golden sheet
Of light that sparkles
clean and sweet
It throws a pattern
on the rooftop floor
Like a map to an open door
I look at the light in your dark eyes
A shimmer that took me by surprise
The world below is a glowing sea
And it feels so quiet and free
Oh, see the sunlight refraction
Shimmering bright on the city skyline
A golden chain of beauty and light
Making the ordinary look divine
I see the reflection on your sleeve
And it's a beauty I can believe
The vibraphone plays a glassy note
Like a message that we wrote
It floats along the dusty breeze
Moving through the rooftop trees
We watch the sparkles fade and glow
In a rhythm that is soft and slow
Oh, see the sunlight refraction
Shimmering bright on the city skyline
A golden chain of beauty and light
Making the ordinary look divine
I see the reflection on your sleeve
And it's a beauty I can believe
The light is bending through the air
Scatter of gold dust on your hair
A shimmery path we didn't plan
Catching the rays while we can
Oh, see the sunlight refraction
Shimmering bright on the city skyline
Making the ordinary look divine
At the end of the day
A final sparkle on the glass pane
A shimmery melody that will remain
(Vibraphone fades out gently)
Gold and bright
Into the night
Leaning back against the clay
Holding the warmth of the day
The air is turning sharp and cold
But these red bricks
are strong and old
They soaked up all the afternoon sun
And they're not letting
go now the day is done
I press my shoulder
to the rough red face
Finding my comfort
in this quiet place
You lean beside me, close and warm
A simple shelter
from the coming storm
We feel the solid
brick behind our spine
A steady anchor in the passing time
The brick wall is holding the heat
While the cold wind
moves down the street
We don't have to say what we mean
Just leaning back, safe and serene
Keeping the warmth that we found
High above the cold ground
The texture of the mortar line
Is rough and dry, but it feels fine
It's real and simple, built to stay
Outlasting the rush of the busy day
We don't need a fancy place to meet
Just a brick wall holding the heat
The brick wall is holding the heat
While the cold wind
moves down the street
We don't have to say what we mean
Just leaning back, safe and serene
Keeping the warmth that we found
High above the cold ground
The sun has slipped below the line
But the wall is warm,
and you are mine
In this quiet corner,
safe from the cold
We have a simple warmth to hold
The brick wall is holding the heat
Keeping our comfort complete
Just leaning back, safe and serene
High above the street
Red clay holding the warm afternoon
Under the light of the rising moon
Still warm, still here
Blowing clear
A hundred lights begin to glow
In the quiet streets below
First a yellow dot along the street
Then a red tail-light
where the avenues meet
One by one, the lanes are waking up
Like sugar dissolving in a coffee cup
The grid is shining
in the deep blue dark
From the corner store
to the quiet park
The world down there is loud and fast
But up here, the quiet moments last
I look at the avenues
starting to gleam
A beautiful, glowing, electric stream
See the blinking city below
A thousand little lights in a row
We are so small in this giant place
But I see the light
on your gentle face
And I feel safe, I feel at ease
Sitting high above the city breeze
The headlights crawl in a steady line
Like stars that decided to align
You point to a tiny yellow spark
A streetlamp warming up the dark
We trace the routes we used to take
And the quiet memories we would make
See the blinking city below
A thousand little lights in a row
We are so small in this giant place
But I see the light
on your gentle face
And I feel safe, I feel at ease
Sitting high above the city breeze
The sky is dark blue,
the grid is bright gold
A beautiful map for
the night to unfold
And though the city is vast and wide
I have everything I
need right by my side
See the blinking city below
A thousand little lights in a row
I feel safe, I feel at ease
High above the breeze
Yellow lights, red and white
Shining through the quiet night
Blinking down below
In a steady glow
A sudden gust from the western sky
Lifting the stray strands high
The wind is playing a playful game
With no rules that we have to name
It sweeps across the concrete floor
And knocks against the metal door
It catches your hair
and spins it round
Lifting the dark
strands off the ground
You try to smooth it with your hand
Laughing at the wind across the land
The serious mood is swept away
By the breezy end of the day
I see you smile, so bright and free
And it's the only view I need to see
Oh, wind-tangled hair
in the afternoon breeze
Spinning around with
the greatest of ease
No need to fix it, no need to care
Just letting the wind blow everywhere
A happy rush in the golden air
With your wind-tangled hair
One strand is caught across your face
You tuck it back with a simple grace
The breeze is blowing our doubts away
Leaving us with nothing left to say
We watch a leaf spin round and round
Before it settles on the ground
Oh, wind-tangled hair
in the afternoon breeze
Spinning around with
the greatest of ease
No need to fix it, no need to care
Just letting the wind blow everywhere
A happy rush in the golden air
With your wind-tangled hair
It blows from the north,
it blows from the south
Putting a happy laugh in your mouth
A simple wind-tangled moment we share
Without a single worry or care
Wind-tangled hair in
the afternoon breeze
Spinning around with
the greatest of ease
A happy rush in the golden air
With your wind-tangled hair
The gust is settling back to a sigh
Underneath the darkening sky
Your hair is messy,
but you don't mind
A simple joy we designed
A quiet pause before we speak
Leaning against the railing peak
(Soft piano chords open slowly)
You start a sentence, then let it go
The words are moving too fast or slow
I look at the sky and hold my breath
No need to speak
this feeling to death
The silence between
us is wide and deep
A beautiful secret we can keep
No need to explain, no need to fill
The quiet air that is standing still
Your presence is enough for me
In this space where we can just be
Oh, the silence between
two words we share
Is warmer than the talk anywhere
We don't have to talk,
we don't have to try
Underneath the deep blue sky
Just a quiet breath, a gentle pause
Silence is our only laws
The piano plays a simple key
Like the pulse of you and me
A long rest in the sheet of song
Where we both feel we belong
You look at me with a steady eye
And let the quiet night draw nigh
Oh, the silence between
two words we share
Is warmer than the talk anywhere
We don't have to talk,
we don't have to try
Underneath the deep blue sky
Just a quiet breath, a gentle pause
Silence is our only laws
Sometimes the words
can get in the way
Of what our hearts are trying to say
But in this pause, the truth is clear
I am safe when you are near
Oh, the silence between
two words we share
Is warmer than the talk anywhere
Just a quiet breath, a gentle pause
In the golden air
A final note on the ivory key
Fading away for you and me
Unspoken and deep
A promise to keep
Two long shadows on the floor
Stretching towards the metal door
The sun is hitting a low-slung space
Casting an outline on your face
Our shapes are
stretching ten feet long
Like notes in a slow and dusty song
We look like giants on this roof
A playful, quiet, dark-blue proof
The angle is shifting
minute by minute
This golden frame and
the shapes within it
We watch our outlines touch and hold
As the sky turns from orange to gold
Oh, see the golden hour silhouette
Two dark shapes that
will never forget
We're painted in shadow
against the light
At the beautiful edge of the night
Long and lean on the concrete floor
Stretching out towards the door
You raise your hand
and watch the shape
A shadow bird trying to escape
I laugh as my shadow mimics yours
Two giants playing on the floors
The light is fading, the angles bend
But this outline is a steady friend
Oh, see the golden hour silhouette
Two dark shapes that
will never forget
We're painted in shadow
against the light
At the beautiful edge of the night
Long and lean on the concrete floor
Stretching out towards the door
The silhouettes are fading slow
As the sun continues to go
They melt into the darker gray
At the very end of the day
Oh, see the golden hour silhouette
Painted in shadow against the light
Stretching out towards the door
On the concrete floor
The shadows fade into the blue
Leaving just the real me and you
Outline is gone
But we carry on
One bright band of orange fire
Rising higher than the spire
The sun has slipped behind the hill
But the horizon is glowing still
A neon border of peach and gold
A beautiful promise to behold
It divides the day
from the coming night
With a steady, warm, residual light
We lean our elbows on the rail
Watching the fading colors pale
It feels like a door is open wide
To everything we keep inside
Oh, look at the warm horizon line
A glowing border of gold and pine
It tells us the day is nearly done
But tomorrow has already begun
We stand right here
on the edge of the sky
Watching the final light go by
The city lights are sparkling bright
But that orange line
is my favorite sight
It holds the warmth of what we shared
A sign that someone truly cared
You point to the
thin and glowing band
Stretching across the silent land
Oh, look at the warm horizon line
A glowing border of gold and pine
It tells us the day is nearly done
But tomorrow has already begun
We stand right here
on the edge of the sky
Watching the final light go by
It's just a line
between day and night
A temporary, beautiful sight
But it makes me
believe in what's ahead
Just like the simple words you said
Oh, look at the warm horizon line
Telling us tomorrow has already begun
Watching the final light go by
On the edge of the sky
The orange line is turning thin
As the blue hour starts to win
A warm horizon, safe and clear
With you near
No need to pack, no need to go
The twilight wind is soft and slow
The streets below are rushing fast
But we've made these hours last
The stars are peaking
through the blue
And I'm still sitting here with you
We didn't plan to stay this late
But neither of us
wants to open the gate
The cold is creeping in our bones
But the rooftop bricks
are familiar stones
Your presence keeps the chill away
In the transition of the day
Oh, the comfort of just staying here
With the twilight settling near
We don't need a promise or a plan
Just holding onto this
moment while we can
A quiet gratitude in the dark
Above the streets and the silent park
You pull your cardigan
tight and close
This is the moment that matters most
No demands for what comes next
No complicated, heavy text
Just the breathing of the city air
And knowing that we both care
Oh, the comfort of just staying here
With the twilight settling near
We don't need a promise or a plan
Just holding onto this
moment while we can
A quiet gratitude in the dark
Above the streets and the silent park
The sky is turning a deep dark gray
As the last of the light fades away
But we linger on the concrete floor
Not quite ready to head for the door
Oh, the comfort of just staying here
With the twilight settling near
A quiet gratitude in the dark
Above the silent park
We stay a little longer in the cold
A simple comfort to have and hold
Not wanting the afternoon to end
My quiet friend
(Melody ends on an unresolved chord)
The key clicks in the rooftop door
We won't see the concrete floor
Descending slow in
the deep blue light
At the very start of the night
The metal steps are cold and neat
Making a hollow sound under our feet
We hold the railing as we go down
Leaving the roof above the town
The blue hour has fully arrived
Where all our quiet thoughts survived
We look up one last time at the sky
Where the golden birds used to fly
The door is waiting
at the bottom stair
But we carry the warmth
we gathered there
Twilight on the metal stairs
Walking down to the street below
We carry the golden
hour in our hearts
In a quiet and steady glow
Leaving the roof to the night
Under the fading blue light
The street-level hum is getting near
But our quiet world is safe and clear
We reach the bottom of the flight
And step out into the city night
A gentle look, a quiet smile
We stood above the world for a while
Twilight on the metal stairs
Walking down to the street below
We carry the golden
hour in our hearts
In a quiet and steady glow
Leaving the roof to the night
Under the fading blue light
The metal rails are cold to touch
But we don't need to say too much
The stairs are behind
us, high and dark
As we walk towards the quiet park
Twilight on the metal stairs
Leaving the roof behind
We carry the golden hour
In our mind
The metal stairs fade in the dark
We step out past the streetlamp mark
Blue hour is complete
Back on the quiet street